[
    
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"5 Books and 7 pens together cost Rs. 79 whereas 7 books and 5 pens together cost Rs. 77, find the total cost of 1 book and 2 pens.",
        "options":
        [
            "Rs. 25",
            "Rs. 40",
            "Rs. 30",
            "Rs. 20"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Rs. 20"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"7 audio casettes and 3 video casettes cost Rs. 1110, while 5 audio casettes and 4 video casettes cost Rs. 1350. Find the cost of an audio casette and a video casette.",
        "options":
        [
            "Audio = Rs. 20, Video = Rs 350",
            "Audio = Rs. 30, Video = Rs 300",
            "Audio = Rs. 30, Video = Rs 400",
            "Audio = Rs. 35, Video = Rs 500"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Audio = Rs. 30, Video = Rs 300"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"3 bags and 4 pens together cost Rs. 257 whereas 4 bags and 3 pens together cost Rs. 324. FInd the total cost of 1 bag and 10 pens.",
        "options":
        [
            "Rs. 155",
            "Rs. 165",
            "Rs. 150",
            "Rs. 170"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Rs. 155"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"3 tables and 5 chairs together cost RS. 3555, while 7 tables and 4 chairs together cost Rs. 5788. Find the cost of a table and that of the chair.",
        "options":
        [
            "Table = Rs. 645, Chair = Rs 377",
            "Table = Rs. 650, Chair = Rs 365",
            "Table = Rs. 660, Chair = Rs 330",
            "Table = Rs. 640, Chair = Rs 327"
        ],
        "correctAns": "Table = Rs. 640, Chair = Rs 327"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The sum of two numbers is 128 and their difference is 16. Find the numbers.",
        "options":
        [
            "70 and 66",
            "75 and 50",
            "72 and 56",
            "82 and 60"
        ],
        "correctAns": "72 and 56"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"Two numbers differ by 3 and their product is 52. Find the numbers.",
        "options":
        [
            "9 and 6",
            "6 and 9",
            "10 and 12",
            "15 and 9"
        ],
        "correctAns": "9 and 6"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The age of father is 3 years more than 3 times the son's age. 3 years hence, the age of the father will be 10 years more than twice the age of the son. Find the present age of son?",
        "options":
        [
            "11 years",
            "12 years",
            "10 years",
            "15 years"
        ],
        "correctAns": "10 years"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The sum of a two digit number and the number obtained by reversing the order of its digits is 165. If the digits differ by 3. Find the number.",
        "options":
        [
            "69",
            "60",
            "59",
            "40"
        ],
        "correctAns": "69"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"A two digit number is four times the sum of its digits and twice the product of the digits. Find the number.",
        "options":
        [
            "40",
            "36",
            "45",
            "30"
        ],
        "correctAns": "36"
    },
    {
        "QorL":"Q",
        "question":"The sum of the numerator and denominator of a fraction is 4 more than twice the numerator. If the numerator and denomenator are increased by 3, they are in ratio 2:3. determine the fractions.",
        "options":
        [
            "x/y = 6/9",
            "x/y = 5/10",
            "x/y = 3/9",
            "x/y = 5/9"
        ],
        "correctAns": "x/y = 5/9"
    }
]
